A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare Interests - Youth, Series R FA327
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Maine - Bar Harbor, 1933-1949 (Box 29, Folder 0300A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Maine - Bar Harbor - Mr. Dana's Salary, 1931-1933 (Box 29, Folder 301)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge for Mr. Dana's work for Mt. Desert Larger Parish.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Maine - Bar Harbor - February 7, 1950 Pledge, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 302)
    $2,500 John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Study of Religious and Social Problems in Bar Harbor, Maine, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 303)
    Survey undertaken by Institute of Social and Religious Research; copy in file.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Massachusetts - Springfield, 1928-1929 (Box 29, Folder 304)
    Standard Oil of New Jersey contribution to building fund; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. J. Hicks, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Massachusetts - Training School, 1901-1913 (Box 29, Folder 305)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge to Springfield school for current expenses, renewal, activities; pledge for plant enlargement and construction. Summary of contributions. Correspondents include L. L. Doggett, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Massachusetts - Training School, 1914-1932 (Box 29, Folder 306)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield, 1933-1942 (Box 29, Folder 307)
    College activities; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to L. L. Doggett Travel Fund; sending of 50th Anniversary Plate; development of College for overseas training service. Other pledges; proposed International Education Center; John D. Rockefeller 3rd interest. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, L. L. Doggett, Edgar B. Young, D. C. Stone.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield, 1943-1953 (Box 29, Folder 308)
    See also Box 47, Folder 544.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield, 1953-1961 (Box 30, Folder 309)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield - January 3, 1929 Pledge, 1928-1929 (Box 30, Folder 310)
    Status of Alumni Hall Fund; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield - April 4, 1930 Pledge, 1929-1934 (Box 30, Folder 311)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to endowment fund; November 9, 1933 gift.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Training School - Springfield - June 16, 1921 and March 1925 Pledges, 1920-1939 (Box 30, Folder 312)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Michigan - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 1905-1928 (Box 30, Folder 313)
    Need for Young Men's Christian Association building at Ann Arbor campus; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge made through Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, R. S. Copeland, John R. Mott, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Minnesota - University of Minnesota, 1911-1928 (Box 30, Folder 314)
    Campaign to raise funds for new building; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Mississippi - Mississippi Agricultural and Mechanical College, 1911-1950 (Box 30, Folder 315)
    Memorandum on Willard S. Richardson visit to College; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge to building fund. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Wickliffe Rose.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New Jersey - Elizabeth, 1919-1933 (Box 30, Folder 316)
    Contributions by Standard Oil of New Jersey and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to building funds campaign; expiration of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas B. Appleget, C. J. Hicks.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New Jersey - Jersey City, 1920-1956 (Box 30, Folder 317)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to million dollar campaign fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. J. Hicks, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New Jersey - Bayonne, 1913-1952 (Box 30, Folder 318)
    Citizens of Bayonne wanted a Young Men's Christian Association; Rockefellers contribute $200,000; relations between Central YMCA and Industrial YMCA In Bayonne. 1938 contribution to help liquidate YMCA debt. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New Jersey - Lakewood, 1905-1929 (Box 30, Folder 319)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions to general budget and activities of Lakewood Young Men's Christian Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New Jersey - Lakewood, 1930-1947 (Box 30, Folder 320)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York State Executive Committee, 1909-1942 (Box 30, Folder 321)
    Reports on activities, finances; contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Fred Eldridge.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to fund for Boys' Building for West Side Young Men's Christian Association, cancellation; his comments on centennial dinner; John D. Rockefeller 3rd talk to West Side YMCA; retirement of Mr. Diack; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller acceptance of dinner patron invitation; World War II YMCA activities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd declined chairmanship of New York City Boys' and Youths' Committee; John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller decline various posts and invitations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Winthrop Aldrich, Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, F. M. Totten, H. Fish.
    - YMCA - New York City, 1920-1940 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    - YMCA - New York City, 1920-1940 (Box 31, Folder 0322A)
    - YMCA - New York City, 1940-1949 (Box 31, Folder 323)
    - YMCA - New York City, 1940-1949 (Box 31, Folder 0323A)
    - YMCA - New York City, 1949-1960 (Box 31, Folder 324)
    - YMCA - New York City, 1949-1960 (Box 31, Folder 0324A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - International Community Center, 23rd Street Branch, 1925-1926 (Box 31, Folder 325)
    Methods of working with foreign groups; Center's needs; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to budget.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions, 1898-1917 (Box 31, Folder 326)
    Summary of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions, 1890-1898; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions; contribution to cover cost of survey of education work; contributions by Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, other members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. L. Dodge, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Willard S. Rockefeller, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, W. T. Diack.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions, 1919-1934 (Box 31, Folder 327)
    See also Box 46, Folder 529.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions, 1937-1949 (Box 31, Folder 328)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions, 1950-1956 (Box 31, Folder 329)
    See also Box 46, Folders 530-532.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - January 3, 1946 Gift, 1945-1946 (Box 31, Folder 330)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave 1,200 shares of Standard Oil stock to Capital Funds Program.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Building Fund, 1910-1917 (Box 32, Folder 331)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller gave $400,000 to $4,000,000 Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Miss Grace Dodge, George W. Perkins.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Building Program and Survey, 1924-1929 (Box 32, Folder 332)
    Projected building program; report of Survey Commission; appeals for funds; needs of West 135th Street Branch. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard, C. L. Dodge, W. T. Diack.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Building Program and Survey - April 26, 1927 Pledge, 1927-1930 (Box 32, Folder 333)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to current expenses and Building Campaign Fund; stipulations regarding distribution of donation; pledge extension.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Hartford House, 1932-1933 (Box 32, Folder 334)
    Expenditures, employment project at House; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution; Mr. Babcock's allegations regarding mismanagement of House. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Students' Club, Intercollegiate Branch, 1899-1918 (Box 32, Folder 335)
    Plans for erection of building for use as club house for College of Physicians and Surgeons students in New York City; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledges to Student Club; designation of part of fund for Graduate Department work. Pledges to work Intercollegiate Young Men's Christian Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Wellington Tinker, Orrin G. Cocks.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Sperry Trust Fund, 1932-1937 (Box 32, Folder 336)
    Death of Elmer A. Sperry; gift of stock to Brooklyn and Queens Young Men's Christian Association; transfer of income to Anniversary Fund. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agreement to count Fund as part of pledge. Arthur W. Packard, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Centennial Fund, 1951-1952 (Box 32, Folder 337)
    $10,000,000 fund-raising campaign to be begun on the centennial year of the founding of the New York City Young Men's Christian Association; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined to join Committee for Centennial Drive. Yorke Allen's report on New York City YMCA; contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Letters of appreciation. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Newbold Morris, Cleveland Dodge, Yorke Allen, Frank Totten, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - October 26, 1951 Pledge (Box 32, Folder 338)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500,000, and an additional $500,000 if the Young Men's Christian Association collected $5,000,000.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Brooklyn, 1902-1924 (Box 32, Folder 339)
    Activities of the Young Men's Christian Association; needs of branches; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution to building fund; annual contributions, declination of invitations to speak. Correspondents include F. B. Pratt, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, J. D. Greene, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, Edward P. Lyon.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Brooklyn, 1927-1956 (Box 32, Folder 340)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Brooklyn - July 10, 1923 Pledge, 1922-1926 (Box 33, Folder 341)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to building needs; extension of expiration date.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Brooklyn - March 10, 1927 Pledge, 1927-1928 (Box 33, Folder 342)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge toward indebtedness; contribution to cover cost of Brooklyn survey.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Brooklyn - December 1928 Appeal, 1928-1932 (Box 33, Folder 343)
    Survey of Brooklyn and Queens Association needs and activities; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to 75th Anniversary Fund.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem Branch, 1944-1956 (Box 33, Folder 344)
    Declinations of appeals and invitations; John D. Rockefeller 3rd 1949 anonymous contribution to Robinson-Campanella program. 1949 address to Century Club. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Jackie Robinson, Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem Branch, 1944-1956 (Box 33, Folder 0344A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem Branch - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Address, 1949-1950 (Box 33, Folder 345)
    Background material used in writing address; publication; copy of talk.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem Branch - Contributions, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 346)
    David Rockefeller gave $1,000; John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave $2,500. Nonrecurring gifts.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem Branch - Contributions, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 0346A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Greater New York, 1957-1961 (Box 33, Folder 347)
    Merger of Young Men's Christian Associations of New York City and Brooklyn/Queens in 1957; constitution and bylaws of new organization. Public opinion poll project; various other projects. Declination of appeals from individual YMCAs and speaking invitations. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Yorke Allen, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Greater New York, 1957-1961 (Box 33, Folder 0347A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Greater New York - Contributions, 1957-1960 (Box 33, Folder 348)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $4,000 annually, 1957-1960; large contribution toward merger expenses, 1957; Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, G. J. Lathrop, Robert S. Curtiss.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown
    Needs and activities of Tarrytown Young Men's Christian Association; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. participation in anniversary celebration. Clippings; the "Negro Issue;" 1958 study of fund-raising possibilities; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift to Phillip Miller for personal use; 1952 gift for rehabilitation fund. Laurance S. Rockefeller activity regarding cooperative project for White Plains and Tarrytown YMCAs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, R. A. Patteson, L. Sleinkofer, Phillip Miller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1903-1916 (Box 33, Folder 349)
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1917-1940 (Box 33, Folder 350)
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1941-1949 (Box 33, Folder 351)
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1942-1961 (Box 33, Folder 0351A)
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1951-1961 (Box 33, Folder 352)
    - YMCA - New York - Tarrytown, 1959-1961 (Box 33, Folder 0352A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - Contribution, May 11, 1936, Boys' Work, 1935-1936 (Box 34, Folder 353)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to develop facilities and program for boys.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - Renovations, 1941-1943 (Box 34, Folder 354)
    Rehabilitation of building; pledges from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his children; deferring of rebuilding for duration of the war.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - Renovations, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 0354A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 Pledge, 1959-1961 (Box 34, Folder 355)
    For Building and Expansion Fund. Lists of Rockefeller gifts to Young Men's Christian Association and to other building funds in Tarrytown area; details of building and renovation plans and needs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. condition gift; paid $218,000; clippings regarding gift. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, A. A. Buzzi, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 Pledge, 1958-1961 (Box 34, Folder 0355A)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Tarrytown - Rehabilitation Fund Campaign, 1948-1958 (Box 34, Folder 356)
    Booklet.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Westchester County Committee, 1909-1930 (Box 34, Folder 357)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to expenses of introducing Young Men's Christian Association work into County. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Sloane, Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - Westchester County Committee - Camp, 1925-1960 (Box 34, Folder 358)
    Plans for summer camp; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to property cost; additional contributions for Camp Sloane; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 gift. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur Woods, Kenneth Chorley, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - New York - White Plains, 1905-1947 (Box 34, Folder 359)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution to building fund; reports of activities. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, W. E. Lougee.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - North Carolina - Blue Ridge Association, 1909-1939 (Box 34, Folder 360)
    Needs for training and conference site; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution for property and construction costs; pledge to summer schools. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John R. Mott, W. D. Weatherford, Jackson Davis.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - North Carolina - College of Agriculture, West Raleigh, 1910-1913 (Box 34, Folder 361)
    Appeal for funds to erect student social and religious life center; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions, conditions of pledge. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, D. H. Hill.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - North Dakota Agricultural College - Fargo, 1916-1926 (Box 35, Folder 362)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge to building fund; declination of appeal for contribution to endowment fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Roy Sweetman.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Ohio - Cleveland, 1896-1913 (Box 35, Folder 363)
    Summary of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledges to 1895; reports of activities; pledges through the Rockefeller Foundation; declination of later appeals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur Woods, Thomas B. Appleget, Charles O. Heydt, G. Shurtleff, C. Terrill, J. Cowles.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Ohio - Cleveland, 1914-1957 (Box 35, Folder 364)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Ohio - Cleveland - Building Campaign, 1910 (Box 35, Folder 365)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Ohio - Collingwood, 1905-1908 (Box 35, Folder 366)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Ohio - Flood District, 1913-1914 (Box 35, Folder 367)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions to replace buildings damaged by floods in Dayton, Hamilton, and Marietta, Ohio. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Robert W. Gumbel, Mabel T. Boardman.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Pennsylvania - Oil City, 1898-1937 (Box 35, Folder 368)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution to Oil City Young Men's Christian Association.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - South Carolina - Clemson Agricultural College, 1913-1959 (Box 35, Folder 369)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge; address by President of Board of Trustees; plans for bronze tablet bearing donor's name. Correspondents include Star J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, W. M. Riggs.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Tennessee - Southern College, Nashville, Dr. Weatherford, 1919-1934 (Box 35, Folder 370)
    Material regarding Negro life; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to budget, deficit, repairs, new building. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Charles O. Heydt, Arthur W. Packard, Dr. W. D. Weatherford.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Tennessee - Young Men's Christian Association Graduate School, Nashville, 1930-1935 (Box 35, Folder 371)
    Printed materials; appeal for contribution to Extension Program; Arthur W. Packard report on training agencies. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. D. Weatherford, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Tennessee - Young Men's Christian Association Graduate School, Nashville - Mr. Packard's Report, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 372)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Tennessee - Peabody College for Teachers, Nashville, 1912-1920 (Box 35, Folder 373)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. pledge for social-religious activities building; working of building inscription; hanging of Sargent portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. at College. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Wallace Buttrick.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Texas - Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas, College Station, 1911-1959 (Box 36, Folder 374)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. $30,000 pledge for Young Men's Christian Association building; 1959 question of legal use of building. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Dana S. Creel, D. F. Houston.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Texas - University of Texas, Austin, 1910-1959 (Box 36, Folder 375)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contribution to Young Men's Christian Association. Correspondents include Star J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget, W. T. Mather.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Virginia - Norfolk Navy Young Men's Christian Association, 1933-1959 (Box 36, Folder 376)
    Photo of bronze tablet at Norfolk YMCA; report of post-1909 activities. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard, Admiral J. K. Taussig.
    See also Box 46, Folder 533.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - Washington - University of Washington, Seattle, 1920-1928 (Box 36, Folder 377)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution for new Young Men's Christian Association building at Seattle university. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1896-1959 (Box 45, Folder 505)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1900-1961 (Box 45, Folder 506)
  - Young Men's Christian Association - International Committee - Statements re Gifts, 1922-1926 (Box 46, Folder 523)
    Statement of the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial - appropriations to Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association to the end of 1924, 3 pages.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - National Council, 1925-1947 (Box 46, Folder 524)
    1) Plan of organization: National Council of Young Men's Christian Association 2) Chart A: Program and Research; May 1, 1952, two pages.
  - Young Men's Christian Association - National Council, 1925-1947 (Box 46, Folder 525)
    Comparative statement of income and expenditures, 1921-1925.